Edna O'Brien papers, circa 1939-2000
Emory University
Edna O'Brien papers, circa 1939-2000
O'Brien, Edna.
Manuscript Collection No. 855
46.75 linear ft. (95 boxes), 8 DVD, and 22 oversized papers (OP)
Literary and personal papers of Irish author Edna O'Brien from circa 1939-2000.
Emory University Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library
Source
Purchase, 2000.
Restrictions on access
Special restrictions apply: Subseries 1.5, entire subseries is closed to researchers, including letters from Marie Heaney.
Series 2, Journals, are closed to researchers and Series 5, Subject files, contains some material which is closed to researchers.
Collection stored off-site. Researchers must contact MARBL in advance to access this collection.
Biographical Note
Edna O'Brien, novelist, short story writer, playwright, and screenwriter, was born December 15, 1932, in Tuamgraney, County Clare, Ireland. Educated first at the local national school and then in a convent, she escaped rural life by attending Pharmaceutical College in Dublin. In 1952, she eloped with Czech-Irish author Ernest Gébler. They moved first to County Wicklow, and then to London, where O'Brien has remained. They divorced after twelve years of marriage, and she raised their two sons alone.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of the literary and personal papers of Irish born author Edna O'Brien from 1939-2000. The bulk of the collection consists of drafts of O'Brien's writings including drafts of her novels, poetry, and short stories. Also present are extensive files of personal and literary correspondence including letters from Samuel Beckett, Harold Pinter, John Osborne, Woody Allen, Robert Graves, Ted Hughes, Saul Bellow, Jacqueline Onassis, Quentin Bell, Sir Ian McKellen, Bill and Hilary Clinton, Tony Blair, and John Major. The collection also includes writings by others (including Harold Pinter), subject files, collected printed material either by or about O'Brien, audio-visual material, and ephemera.
Arrangement Note
Organized into nine series: (1) Correspondence, (2) Journals, (3) Writings by O’Brien, (4) Writings by others, (5) Subject files, (6) Printed material, (7) Audio-visual material, (8) Ephemera, and (9) Collected material.
Selected Search Terms
Personal Names
Beckett, Samuel, 1906-; Bell, Quentin.; Graves, Robert, 1895-; Heaney, Seamus, 1939-; Hughes, Ted, 1930-1998.; Osborne, John, 1929-; Pinter, Harold, 1930-
Topical Terms
English literature--Irish authors--20th century.; English poetry--Irish authors.; Women authors, Irish--20th century.; Women poets, Irish--20th century.
Form/Genre Terms
Manuscripts.; Plays.; Poems.; Scripts.; Sound recordings.; Photographs.; Video recordings.
Occupation
Woman poet.; Woman author.
Description of Series
- Correspondence, 1939-2000, Series 1; Boxes 1-18
  Scope and Content Note
  The correspondence series in the Edna O'Brien papers includes letters dating from ca. 1939-2000. The five subseries are categories created by O'Brien, which have been organized chronologically. Alphabetical correspondence includes correspondents: Samuel Beckett, Harold Pinter, John Osborne, Woody Allen, Robert Graves, Ted Hughes, Saul Bellow, Jacqueline Onassis, Quentin Bell, Sir Ian McKellen, Bill and Hilary Clinton, and Tony Blair, as well as numerous editors, publishers and press agents. Family correspondents, Subseries 1.2, include O'Brien's parents, Michael and Helena; O'Brien (Cleary), her ex-husband, Ernest Gebler, and her sons, Carlos and Sasha Gebler. Subseries 1.3, Personal correspondence, includes general correspondence from friends and colleagues. O'Brien's fan correspondence, Subseries 1.4, contains letters of thanks and criticism from readers of her work. Subseries 1.5 contains the Restricted correspondence of Marie; Heaney, John Fortune, David Owen, Peter Reed, and Goran Palin.
  Restrictions on access
  Special restrictions apply: Subseries 1.5, entire subseries is closed to researchers, including letters from Marie Heaney.
  Arrangement Note
  Organized into five subseries: (1.1) Alphabetical correspondence, (1.2) Family correspondence, (1.3) Personal correspondence, (1.4) Fan correspondence, and (1.5) Restricted correspondence.
  - Alphabetical correspondence, 1955-2000, Subseries 1.1; Boxes 1-12
    Arranged in alphabetical order.
    - Abbey, Edward, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Abbey Theatre, 1977-1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - ABC Films, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Aberystwyth Arts Festival, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Adamucci Jr., Frank, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - The Adelaide Festival of Arts, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Aer Lingus, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ahern, Bertie, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ahern, Rosemary, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Aitken, Stone, and Wylie, 1989-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Albee, Edward, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Aldrin, Buzz, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Algeo, Margaret, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Allan, Diana, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Allan, Norman, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Allen, Ted, 1959-1991 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Allen, Woody, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Alexander, Brian, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Alitalia, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Allsop, Kenneth, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Alltransport International Group, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Almeida Theatre, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Alvarez, A., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - American Irish Historical Society, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Amis, Kingsley, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Ammi, Almi, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Anderson, Ernie, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Anderson, Mary, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Anderson, Michael, 1993-1999 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Angell, Roger, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Anthony, Paul, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Aosdana, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - The Apollo Society, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Arbeid, Ben, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Armao, Agnes, 1989-1998 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Arnott, John, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Article 19, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - The Arts Council of Great Britain, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Arts Society, University College Galway, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Ashford Castle, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Astor, Alastair, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Astor, Mrs. Vincent, undated [to Jacqueline Kennedy Onassis] (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - The Athena Foundation, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Atheneum Publishers, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Athill, Diana, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Austin, M., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - A-unidentified (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Ball, Dennis, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Ballynahinch Castle, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Banton, John, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Banville, John, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Barbican Centre, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Barbican Library, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Barclays Bank Ltd., 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Barker Publishers, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Barnett, Gene, undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Barr, Ann, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Barrington, Edward, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Barton, Don, undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Baudrand, Jean, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Bauer, Lib, undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - BBC, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Beckett, Samuel, 1969-1986 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Behan, John, 1993-1998 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Bell, Quentin, 1977-1987 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Bellow, Saul, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Benaim, S., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Benedictus, David, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Benn, Tony, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Bennett, Jill, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Bennett, Margaret R., 1994 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Benton, William, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Beresford, Bruce, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Berger, John, 1961-1994 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Berk, Lotte, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Bernheim, Alain, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Berry, E., 1967 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - De Bezige Bij, 1995-1999 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Bicknell, Terry, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Biderman, Sol, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Birkett, Michael, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Birtwistle, Sue, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Black, Conrad, undated (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Blair, Tony [and Office of the Prime Minister], 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Bloom, Claire, undated (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Boatwright, Boaty, undated (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - The Bodley Head Ltd., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Booker Prize for Fiction, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Books and Bookmen, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Boorman, John, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - Boose, Andrew, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Boston Public Library, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Bourke, John, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Bower, Warren, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Boyd, Madeline, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Brady, Siobhan, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Brandt, Bill, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Bratby, John, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - British Safety Council, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Brittenden, Arthur, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Brodie, Alan, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Brogan, Bill, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Brook, Peter, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Brooke, Jeremy, 1960 and undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Brophy, Brigid, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Brown Jr., Edmund, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Brown, Gordon, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Browne, Vincent, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Bruce, Evangeline, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Bryce, Hammer and Co., 1966-1970 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Bucher Publishers Ltd., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Buck, Jules, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Buckman, Peter, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Buckner, Adrian, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Burton, Humphrey, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Burton, Richard, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Busby, Robert, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - B--unidentified (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Cahill, Eileen, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Calder and Boyars, Ltd., 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Calder, Liz, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Cambridge University English Club, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Campbell, David, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Campbell, Hooper and Co., 1963 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Cape, Jonathan, 1961-1992 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Caponetto, Edna, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Capper, Alan, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Carmody, John, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Caroffo, Piera Mancioochi, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Caron, Leslie, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Carpenter, Elizabeth Lee, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Carter, Graydon, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Casey, Michael, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Cassavetes, John, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Cater, Wendy (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - The Cathkin, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Chalfant, Sarah, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Chang, J., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Chasman, David, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Cheetham, Georgina, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Cheetham, Rosie, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Chelsea College, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Cheltenham Festival, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Chichester Festival Theatre, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Chinqi, Ting, 1992-1999 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Chodorov, Edward, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Christie, Mynetta, 1989-1996 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Churchill, Tom, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Cierach, Liudka, undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - City Arts and Lectures, Inc., 1985 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Clare County Council, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Clarke, Dennis, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Clegg, M., 1961 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Clinton, Bill and Hilary Rodham, 1994-1999 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Club Dell’aretusa, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Cockburn, Alexander, undated (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Codron, Michael, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Cohen, J.M., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Coleridge, Nicholas, undated (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Collins Publishers, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Commins, Dotty, undated (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Connery, Don, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Connolly, Earl, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Connolly, Evelyn, undated (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Connule, Judith, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Conway, Beatrice, undated (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Cooper, Dr. Barrington, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Cooper, Canon, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Corden, Alison, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Cosmopolitan, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - County Clare Vocational Education Committee (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Cournos, Michael, undated (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Craddock, Fanny, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Craigie, J.R., 1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Crawford, Cheryl, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Crewe, Quentin, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Cronin, Bart, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Crowley, Bob, 1991-1999 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Cullitor, Maureen, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Cusack, Cyril, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Cutler, Mary, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - C-unidentified (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Dahl, Gasta, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Daldry, Stephen, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Dalton, Robin, 1966-1996 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Davenport, John, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - David, Elizabeth, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Davids, Roy, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Davis, Desmond, 1965-1992 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Davis, Hunter, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Davis, Pat, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Day, Sir Robin, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Dayan, Ruth, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Deevy, Tom, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Deighton, Len, 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Delage, Florence, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Derkson, Jan, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Desch, Kurt, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Desenberg, B.M., undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Desmond, Dermot, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Deutsch, Andre, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Deutscher, Tamara, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Dewis, Shirley, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Dile, Leo, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Dillon, Edward, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Dillon, John, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Dimou, Fatini, 1995-1999 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Diogenes Verlag AG, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Doctorow, E.L., 1997 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Doherty, James, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Donadia, Candida, 1966-1975 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Donnelly, Marie, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Donner, Jorn, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Drabble, Margaret, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Dunn, Douglas, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Dunn, Nell, 1976 and undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Durbridge, Stephen, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Durrell, Lawrence, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Dutton, F., 1971 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Dunne, Sean, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Dykstra, Gerdien, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Dyson, Margaret, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Dyson, Peter, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - D-unidentified (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Eastwood, Clint, undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Eaton, Kendall, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Edwards, Margaret, 1974-1983 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Eilenberg, Max, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Elliott, Tony, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Ellmann, Richard, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Emerson, Peter Van Dyck, undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Emmons, Ron, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Enniss, Stephen, 1997-2000 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Eskapa, Shirley, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Evans, Laurence and Mary, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Eyre, Richard, 1992-1999 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - E-unidentified (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Faber and Faber, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Falkender, Marie, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Falkus, Gila, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Farrar, Straus, and Giroux Inc., 1984-1997 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Fashion, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Fawcett World Library, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Fea, Valerie, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Fellini, Federico, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Fernandez, Aurora, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Field, Marjorie, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Finney, Albert, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Fitzgerald, Geraldine, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Fitzgerald, T.S., 1965 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Fletcher, Jean, 1992-1998 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Florence, Peter, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Flynn, Kit, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Foinse, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Folkard and Hayward, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Fonda, Jane, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Forest Mere, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Forster, Margaret, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Fortnum and Mason, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Forum, 1965-1970 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Fountain, Lea, 1964-1968 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Fowles, John, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - de Francia, Peter, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Fraser, Benjamin, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Fraser, Hugh, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Freeman, John, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Friedman, Bruce Jay, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Friel, Brian, 1962-1993 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Frasch, William A., 1999 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Frost, David, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Fry, Tim, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - F-unidentified (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Galassi, Jonathan, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Gallagher, Rory, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Garland, Patrick, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - The Gate, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Gay, Kristen Marie, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - George, Terry, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Gerhardi, William, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Gilliatt, Penelope, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Godwin, Tony, 1967-1976 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Goff, Martyn, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Gold, Don, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Goldstein, Sydney, 1993-1997 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Goodman, Derrick and Co., 1977 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Goodman, Edward, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Gorbachov, Mikael, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Gordon, Dr. James Dula, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Gordon, Mary, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Gordon’s Wine Bar, undated (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Gothard, David, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Gottlieb, Bob, 1965-1969 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Gourmet, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Graham, Robert Douglas, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Graham-Bell, Ann, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Grass, Gunter, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Graves, Robert (Family), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Gray, H., 1962 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Green, Hester, 1962-1978 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Green, Nancie, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Greene, Graham, 1961-1970 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Gregory, Betty, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Gregson, Richard, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Greifer, Lewis, undated (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Grennan, Eamon, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - The Greville Press, undated (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Grimes, Tim, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Groocock, Veronica, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Guinness, Alec, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Gunderud, Evelyn, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Guntern-Gallati, Greta and Gottlieb, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Guyet, Carole, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - G-unidentified (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Hall, Emma, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Hall, Peter, 1973-1992 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Hall, Robert H., undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Hall, Stanley, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Hallman, Frank, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Hamilton, Bill, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Hamilton, Iain, 1960-1961 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Hamish Hamilton Ltd, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Hanley, Geoff, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Hanna, Jack, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1976-1992 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Hare, David, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Harper’s, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Harris, R.E., 1963 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Harris, Stewart, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Harrison, Carey, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Harrod’s, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Hart, Josephine, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Harwood, Ronald, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Hashimi, Aqeel, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Haslam, Nicholas, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Hatchards Booksellers, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Hawes and Co., undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Hawkinson, Norman, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Hayden, Tom, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Hayes, Peter Namdev, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Haynes, Jim, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Heal, Jeanne, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Healy, Ian, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Hearne, Dana, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - A.M. Heath and Co. Ltd., 1960-1998 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Heggie, Don, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Heinecke, William, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Heller, Joseph, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Heller, Paul, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Helms, Adam, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Hendricks, Melanie, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Hennessy, Brenden, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Hennington, Aidan, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Hertel, Hans, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Heyman, Norma, 1993-1998 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Hickman, Mary, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Higgins, John, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Hill, Gladys, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Hill, Susan, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Hillery, Michael, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Hillery, Paddy, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Hillery, P.J., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Hintze, Arnold, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Hockney, David, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Hodgson, Claire, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Hodgson, Pierre, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Hoffman, Lee, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Hoffman, Undcampe, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Hogarth Press Ltd., 1982 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Holden, Ursula, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Holm, Ian, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Horizon Pictures, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Horovitz, Michael, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Horsburgh, Frances, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Houghton Mifflin, 1962-2000 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Houston, Nainsi, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Howard, Elizabeth Jane, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Huckster, Barbara, undated (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Hudson, Geoffry, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Huges, Bart, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Huggel, H.P., 1969 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Hughes, Don, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Hughes, John Williams, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Hughes, Ted, 1982-1997 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Hume, John and Pat, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Humphries, Barry, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Hunt, Pam, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Hunter, Andrew, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Hurley, Graham, undated (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Hurley, Joe, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Hurt, John and Sarah, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Huston, John and Gladys, 1968-1983 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Hutchinson Educational Ltd., 1969 (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - Hutchinson Publishing Group, 1960-1972 (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - H-unidentified (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - The Independent, 1993-1999 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Irish America Magazine, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Irish Times, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Irons, Jeremy, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Isaak, Robert, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - I-unidentified (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Jacobs, Max, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Jacoby, Wynanda, 1995-1999 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Janklow, Morton, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Janni, Joseph, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Johnson, Greg, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Johnson, Marigold, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 12)